<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Rabobank Research RSS feed</title>
    <link>https://research.rabobank.com</link>
    <description>Research Articles</description>
    <language>NL</language>
    <item>
      <title>GBP - trust, buyer's remorse and international reputation</title>
      <link>https://research.rabobank.com/markets/en/documents/293558_FXOutlook110621.pdf</link>
      <author>Jane Foley</author>
      <languagecode>NL</languagecode>
      <language>Dutch</language>
      <publicationlabel />
      <researcharea>Global Economics &amp; Markets</researcharea>
      <sourceid>293557</sourceid>
      <mediatype>FX Outlook</mediatype>
      <year>2021</year>
      <thumbnail>https://research.rabobank.com/markets/en/images/292329_uk%20gbp%20banknotes%202.jpg</thumbnail>
      <pubdate>2021-06-11T16:53:03Z</pubdate>
      <description>It is clearly important to Biden that he uses the first international trip of his presidency to re-frame the US’ relationship with its key allies and re-assert the US’ leadership position on the global stage. The G7 summit is of equal importance to PM Johnson. Not only is he the host, but it is the first major political face-to-face event for the UK post-Brexit. Biden’s stance appears to be working in the PM’s favour. Since the President was more keen to stress the US’ special relationship with the UK than to spark numerous headlines referencing the N. Ireland protocol and peace process, Johnson appeared to have avoided some uncomfortable headlines at the start of Biden’s trip to Cornwall. That said, both the EU and Biden have made their positions with respect to the Northern Ireland protocol very clear. Failure by the UK government to implement the protocol could further delay a trade deal with the US and result in a trade war with the EU, the UK’s largest trading partner. However, as is made clear by another protest in Northern Ireland this week, implementation of the protocol risks stoking the anger of Ulster Unionists and provoking instability in the region. Not only do GBP investors have to negotiate these risks but tensions between the UK and its farmers complicate the potential impact of an imminent UK trade deal with Australia. Another headwind for the pound is the risk that the June 21 planned re-opening of England’s economy will be delayed. While we have not changed our forecast that EUR/GBP could still head to 0.84 by year end, GBP bulls may continue to struggle to make headway vs. the EUR in the near-term.</description>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>
